# **Dalveer Singh**

Full Stack Web Developer (Node, React)

Full stack web developer with 1 Year of experience and the ability to learn and collaborate in rapidly changing environments and compositions. Worked through 1000+ hours of boot camp structure, learning Typescript, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, React.js, Next.js, NoSQL, SQL, REST, GraphQL, and many more.

Status in Canada: Open Work Permit

# **Work History**

Apr 2022 - Nov 2022

# **Full Stack Web Developer**

New World Inc., Toronto

- Worked with Backend developers to develop REST API using Node.js,
  Typescript, Sequelize.js, and PostgresSQL database for the New World
  NET Platform.
- Worked with Front-End Developers to develop React App Using React.js, Redux.js, Typescript, TailwindCSS, etc.

Jan 2022 - Apr 2022

# **Software Developer Intern**

INFOWIZ, Etobicoke, ON

 Working in Node.js, and Next.js environments using a custom Express server.

Lambton College Of Applied Arts And Technology, Toronto, ON

• Building RESTful APIs that serve data to the React front-end.

## **Education**

Sep 2020

- Apr 2022

Computer Software and Database Development

May 2016

- May 2019

## **Bachelor of Computer Application**

Punjabi University, Patiala, Punjab, India

## **Projects**

- Jan 2022 Portfolio Website

https://dalveersidhu.com/

Utilized Node.js, MongoDB, React.js, Next.js, Redux.js, etc.

- Dec 2021 Quiz app Using React and Next.js

https://next-js-quiz-app.vercel.app/

A SPA Quiz app using NEXT.js, Node.js, React.js, Redux.js, etc.

GitHub: https://github.com/dalveersidhu97/NextJs-Quiz-App

- Nov 2021 Project Management System

Utilized Node.js and Express.js, Mongoose, EJS View engine, JWT,

Bootstrap.css, etc.

GitHub: https://github.com/dalveersidhu97/final-project-node

- Sep 2019 Shopping Store

http://desicart.000webhostapp.com/

GitHub: https://github.com/dalveersidhu97/WebProject

## **Personal Info**

### Date of birth

August 15, 1997

### **Email**

dalveersidhu97@gmail.com

#### **Phone**

+1 (902) 988-0900

#### Address

40 Tamworth Court, Brampton Ontario, Canada

#### Website

http://www.dalveersidhu.com/

#### GitHub

https://github.com/dalveersidhu97

## LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dalveersingh-sidhu/

## **Skills**

Typescript, Javascript

Node.js, Next.js, React.js, Express.js

TailwindCSS, Bootstrap

MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQL Server, Oracle Database

mongoose.js, sequelize.js

Redux.js, Socket.io, Websockets, OAuth

Test Driven Development (TDD), Unit Testing

Jest, React Testing Library, Mocha and Chao

REST APIs, GraphQL, MVC

Github, Git, Gitlab

Docker, Kubernetes, Microservices

Agile methodologies, JIRA

Fimiliar with React Native

Knowledge of Java, PHP, Python

JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, SASS